(香燐)あ…
サスケのいた場所に誰かいる。
There's someone else
where Sasuke is.
(大蛇丸)チャクラに覚えは？
Do you recognize the chakra?
No!
ない。 けど…。
But…
(水月)けど 何？
But what?
このチャクラ…。
This chakra…
すごく イヤな感じがする。
…has a real nasty feel to it!
なら もっと急がないとね。
Then we need to hurry even more.
どこの馬の骨かもしれない輩に→
We don't know what
this stranger might do
to Sasuke.
サスケ君が 何されるか
わからないものね。
Is this the end for him?
《彼の風は ここまでかしらね》
《チクショー！》
Damn it…
(水月)うわっ！
(大蛇丸)香燐。
Karin!
If you up the pace too much,
you're going to collapse soon.
だからって そんなに飛ばすと
すぐ バテるわよ。
(ガイ)青春パワー マックスで
みんなのところへ行くぞ リー テンテン。
Let's head to the others with
youth power to the max!
Lee! Tenten!
The Blue Beast vs. Six Paths Madara
(香燐)サスケ!!
Sasuke!
はぁ!? 誰だ アイツ？
Who is that guy?!
(香燐)テメエ！
どこのどいつだか知らねえが→
Hey you!
I don't know who the hell you are,
but what are you doing to Sasuke?
サスケに何してやがる！
なんだよ そういうことか。
ああん？
Oh, so that's what's going on…
Huh?
あなただったのね。
So it was you…
(大蛇丸)カブト。
…Kabuto.
(カブト)ここへ急ぐ一行を
感知してました。
I sensed a group rushing this way…
やはり 大蛇丸様でしたか。
It was you, after all, Lord Orochimaru.
コイツが カブト？ チャクラが違うぞ。
That's Kabuto?!
His chakra is different!
見た目もね。
Even his appearance.
(大蛇丸)いろいろと他人のチャクラを
体に入れ込んだあげく→
He has taken in the chakra
of many people,
仙術チャクラまで取り込んだから→
even Sage Jutsu chakra.
香燐でも別人と間違えたようね。
It's no wonder even you thought
he was someone else, Karin…
ちなみに
イヤな感じがしたのって→
I wonder if his chakra
had a nasty feel to it
私のチャクラが
まだ残っていたからかしら？
because he still has
some of mine inside him?
それとも…。
– Or…
– Get away from Sasuke, you brainy jerk!
サスケから離れろ！
このインテリ野郎！
ここに何をしに
来られたんです？ 大蛇丸様。
What brings you here, Lord Orochimaru?
あなたこそ。
I should ask you the same thing.
《重吾 : どうするつもりだ
大蛇丸》
What are you planning, Orochimaru?
カブトさん まさか サスケまで
取り込む気じゃないよね。
Mister Kabuto…
Don't tell me you're going
to absorb Sasuke?
カブトに サスケで
カブケか サストだか知らないけどさ。
And would that make you
Kabuke or Sasuto?
テメエが サスケをやったんだな！
You're the one who
did this to Sasuke?!
この野郎！
You bastard!
水月 僕は
もうそんなことはしないし→
Suigetsu… I don't desire to
do that anymore.
香燐 僕は もう
サスケ君を奪おうとは思わない。
Nor am I going to steal Sasuke, Karin.
《サスケのチャクラ かすかに感じる。
まさか…》
Sasuke's chakra!
I can faintly sense it!
No way!
カブト アンタが サスケを。
Kabuto… You're helping Sasuke?
そう 僕の医療忍術と
研究し尽くしたあの柱間細胞。
Yes.
With my Medical ninjutsu and
much-tinkered cells of Hashirama,
そして ある方の助言で彼の一命を
どうにか とりとめたんだ。
along with a certain
someone's suggestion,
I managed to stop him from dying.
He's right.
(扉間)そういうことだ。
(水月)あ…。
Huh?!
これはこれは…。
私が最も尊敬する二代目火影…。
Well, well…
if it isn't the man I most respect…
千手扉間様。
the Second Hokage,
Lord Tobirama Senju.
しかし カブト あなたが
ここにいるということは→
However, Kabuto…
You being here means that
イタチのイザナミの術による無限ループから
抜け出せたってことだけど。
you were able to slip out of the infinite loop
set up by Itachi's Izanami?
そうです。 僕は 自分を認めず
何者かもわからないでいた。
You're right.
I was unable to acknowledge myself,
I didn't even know who I was.
それを簡単に教えてくれる
あなたに利用され→
That allowed you to give me
easy answers and use me.
己を失っていった。
Making me lose myself even more.
《カブト : 今までのものが
納得できないなら→
If you're not satisfied with
what you've had so far…
代わりのものを見つけて→
Just find other things and
add them onto yourself…
次々に
足していけばいいだけのこと》
one by one.
((うわ～っ！
まだ まだ足りない…。
It's still…
It's still not enough…
(これは まだ僕じゃない))
This is…still not me!
(カブト)でも イタチはあの術で
僕に気づかせた。
But with that jutsu,
Itachi made me realize…
僕は他でもない カブトなんだと。
that I am none other…than Kabuto…
そして 帰るべき場所も…。
…and where my home is.
なんかさ 中身まで変わった？
Does it seem like the person inside
has changed too?
それが イザナミという術なの。
That is the jutsu known as Izanami.
つまり 己自身を見つめ直し
受け入れなければ→
The jutsu is set up so that
you cannot undo it
until you reflect upon yourself
and accept who you are.
術が解けない仕組みなのよ。
サスケ…。
Sasuke...
(カブト)僕は今 帰るべき場所を
なくしたくないと→
Now I wish from the bottom of my heart
心の底から願うようになった。
to not lose my home.
イタチが 死んでも守りたいと願った
サスケ君…。
And Itachi, who wanted to
protect Sasuke even unto death…
その思いが
痛烈に僕の心を貫いてきた。
His feelings have pierced
through my heart strongly.
フンッ あのね 今更言えた義理かよ！
Hey!
Isn't it a little too late
to say things like that?
アンタさ ニセモノマダラと組んで→
You teamed up with that fake Madara!
この戦争を おっ始めた
首謀者なんだぞ！
You guys started this war!
そのとおりだ。
You're right.
僕も そのオビトも この世の中に→
Both Obito and I…
…thought we'd lost our place in this world.
自分の居場所が
なくなってしまったと思い込み→
皆を巻き込んだ。
And dragged everyone else into this.
だが もう自分が何者か
わかっている。
But, I now know who I am.
そして 己が何をすべきかも。
And what I must do!
(マダラ)増援が来たところで
お前らは ただの砂利。
You may be reinforcements,
but you're nothing more than pebbles.
今更 何もできんぞ。
You won't make any difference
at this point.
ヤツが マダラ？
(カカシ)ああ そうだ。
That's Madara?!
Yes, that's him.
(ミナト)カカシ 大丈夫かい？
Kakashi, are you all right?
はい ガイのおかげで。
Yes, thanks to Guy.
I don't mean that.
(ミナト)いや そっちじゃなくて→
僕の仙法の螺旋丸が当たったほう。
I'm talking about my Sage Art
Rasengan hitting you earlier.
それも大丈夫です。
That was okay too.
跳ね返って当たる瞬間に
神威で飛ばしましたから。
I diverted it with my Kamui
just as it was making contact.
((神威！))
Kamui!
(ミナト)よかった。
仙法？ 仙術ですか？
I'm glad…
Sage Art?
You mean, senjutsu?
そう。 ヤツには 仙術しか効かない。
Yes.
Only senjutsu works against him…
それと もうひとつ…
体術による物理的ダメージ。
As well as…
physical attacks such as taijutsu.
(我愛羅)四代目火影の仙術と ガイ…
あなたの体術しか→
Which means our only hope is
the Fourth Hokage's senjutsu
and your taijutsu, Guy.
今は手段がないということか。
先生は たしか その
仙術があまり…。
If I recall, Sensei,
senjutsu isn't your forte…
そう… 正直 仙術は苦手でね。
Yes.
In all honesty, I'm weak in senjutsu.
チャクラの練り上げに
時間がかかりすぎるうえ→
It takes me too long to infuse the chakra
長時間 維持できない。
and I can't maintain it very long.
実戦でも
あまり使ってこなかったんだ。
I haven't used it very much
in combat either.
そのうえ
今は印が組めない状態だから→
Furthermore, in this state,
I can't weave signs,
so I don't think
I can even fight effectively.
まともに戦うことも
できないと思う。
つまり今 この碧き猛獣の→
So, it's showtime
for the wild blue beast, eh?
出番ということになるな。
八門遁甲！
Eight Inner Gates!
第七驚門！
Seventh Gate of Shock!
開！
Open!
《碧い蒸気…》
Blue vapor?
ガイ！
Guy!
(マダラ)八門遁甲…。
Eight Inner Gates…
死門の１つ前か。
One gate before the Gate of Death…
赤い蒸気にならぬとは
なめられたものだ。
He insults me,
not bringing out the Red Vapor.
黒い玉と棒に触れたらダメだよ！
Don't let the black spheres
or rod touch you!
まさか ガイが八門遁甲を…。
Who could've imagined Guy
mastering the Eight Gates!
人の動きじゃない。
Those are not human movements!
《ガイ : 食らえ！》
Take this!
昼虎！
Hirudora! Afternoon Tiger!
うっ…。
《黒い玉に体当たりしつつ→
I have to use
the Flying Raijin once more
もう一度 飛雷神しかない》
to throw myself into
the Black Sphere's path!
カカシ クナイを！
Kakashi, take the kunai!
はい！
Right!
(リー)ぬお～っ！
ロック・リー！
Rock Lee!
ガイ先生 大丈夫ですか？
Guy Sensei! Are you all right?
あぁ… すまない リー。
Yes. Thanks, Lee.
テンテンは どうした？
How is Tenten?
少し確かめたいことがあるから
先に行けと。
She wanted to check something out,
and made me go on ahead.
やっと追いついた途端
急に昼虎が…。
Just when I was about to catch up...
all of a sudden
the Hirudora appeared.
大丈夫か？ ガイ。
あぁ。
Are you all right, Guy?
Yeah.
右腕と肋骨が数本いってる程度だ。
Only my right arm and
a few ribs are hurt.
頼みの綱の体術もダメとなると
どうする…。
What are we going to do
if our last ray of hope, your taijutsu…
is no good?
(カカシ)ヤツは 強すぎる。
He's…too strong.
Wait, Kakashi…
待て カカシ。 まだ 体術がダメ
と決めつけるのは 早い。
It's too soon to decide
my taijutsu won't work!
But…
しかし…。
俺たちの青春は→
Our youth hasn't faded yet!
まだ色あせちゃいない。
望みを捨てるな！
Do not lose hope!
(リー)ガイ先生。
Guy Sensei…
It's true that everything we wish for
will not come to be...
(ガイ)確かに 望むことが
すべて できるわけじゃない。
But things that we must do
しかし やるべきことは いつも
望んでからでなければ 始まらん。
must always begin with a wish.
お前への挑戦が
そうだったようにな。
Just like the times I challenged you.
((勝負だ カカシ！))
I challenge you, Kakashi!
(ガイ)そして
これは 決して強がりではない。
And this is not a bluff.
お前 まさか…。
Don't tell me...
you're going to—!
木ノ葉の碧き猛獣は 終わり→
The end has come for
the Leaf's Blue Beast…
It's time for the Red Beast to emerge!
紅き猛獣となるときがきたようだ。
まさか 最後の死門を…。
No way… Not the final Gate of Death!
ガイ！ それは ダメだよ。
よく考えるんだ。
Guy! Don't do that!
Think it over hard!
ここにいる誰も
それを望んではいないよ。
No one here wishes for that!
キミの父上だって…。
Not even you father would...
No!
いいえ 俺が望んでいるんです。
But I wish it.
Guy Sensei!
ガイ先生！ ガイ先生にとって
今が ホントに そのときなのですか？
Do you really think it's that time?
リー そんな顔するな。
Lee, don't look at me like that.
今度は お前が笑って見ていろ。
This time, you sit back
and enjoy the show!
You remind me of myself back then,
((ガイ : お前は 俺に よく似てる。
when I was
a complete failure.
昔は この俺も
落ちこぼれだったが→
今じゃ 天才エリート。
Now, in matches against
that elite genius Kakashi,
カカシとの勝負でも
勝ちこしているほどだ。
we're nearly even.
たとえ
忍術や 幻術は 使えなくても→
"Even if I cannot do ninjutsu or genjutsu…
立派な忍者になれることを
証明したいですってな。
I want to prove that can still
become a splendid ninja?"
それが お前の忍道だろ？
Isn't that your Ninja Way?
いい目標じゃないか。
頑張る価値のある いい目標だよ。
That's a fine goal.
It's a goal worth fighting for.
だから お前も
自分の道を信じて突っ走ればいい。
So you must believe in your path
and run hard toward it!
(俺が笑って見てられるくらいの
強い男になれ！))
Become strong so I can just sit back
and enjoy the show!
(ガイ)父さん…。
Father…
Yes, I'm in!
Congratulations!
Not there… not there… not there!
((ガイ : ない ない ない。
ACADEMY ACCEPTANCE RESULTS
Not there… not there… not there…
ない ない ない…。
あっ あった！
There, I see it!
We did it!
やったな！ おめでとう！
Congratulations!
お前 あったか!?
Yes! I got in!
(ダイ)息子よ！ 存分に探せ！
My son, search to your heart's content!
うん？
It's not there…
ないよ… やっぱり どこにも
僕の名前がないよ パパ！
My name is nowhere on the list, Papa!
Then keep on looking, Guy!
探し続けるのだ ガイ！
You have worked hard and
done everything you possibly could.
お前は
出来うるかぎりの努力をした！
その努力が報われぬわけがない。
There is no way all that effort
will not be rewarded.
涙で滲んだ その先に やがて
お前の名前は見つかるだろう。
Those tears are blurring your vision.
You will see your name soon.
はい！
Yes!
Might Guy… Might Guy… Might Guy...
マイト・ガイ マイト・ガイ…。
(ゲンマ)諦めの悪いヤツだな…。
He just won't give up, will he?
It's very unsightly.
(エビス)まったく 見苦しい姿です。
KAKASHI HATAKE
Papa, I'm sorry…
パパ ごめん！
ごめんなさい！
I'm so sorry…
諦めるな ガイ！
Do not give up, Guy!
Don't turn away!
目をそらすな！
きっとある きっと！
You will find it! You will!
ACADEMY ORIENTATION
ハァハァハァ…。
IF I RUN 500 LAPS, I'LL BE ACCEPTED
AS AN ALTERNATE
Isn't that the kid who was making
such a fuss about failing the test?
アイツ 試験に落ちて
大騒ぎしてたヤツじゃねえか？
応援してくれたパパのためにも
絶対に…。
This is for my papa who never
gave up on me too…
I'll definitely get in!
What does he mean by "self rule"?
自分ルールって なんだそれ？
アハハハ！
He can't just decide something like that!
なに勝手に決めてんだよ？
僕は知ってますよ。
I know about it…
He cannot perform ninjutsu
or genjutsu at all.
彼は 忍術も幻術もからっきしで→
The only thing he has going for him
is to move his body around.
体を動かすことくらいしか
アピールできるものがないんですよ。
That may be so,
but he looks ready to drop.
それにしては
もうヘトヘトじゃねえの。
ハァハァハァ…。
Guy, don't give up.
ガイよ… 頑張れ！
だが お前は間違っているぞ。
But you've got it all wrong!
235… 周…。
T-Two hundred thirty-five...laps…
あっ！
ハハハハ！
He's not even half way done!
半分もいってねえじゃねえかよ！
Papa...
パパ…。
Guy! You fool!
ガイ！ このバカ野郎！
うわ～っ！
ご… ごめん パパ！
I'm sorry, Papa…
５歳にもなって
校庭500周すらできないなんて。
I'm already five years old,
but I can't even run 500 laps…
だから謝るな！
そこを叱ったんじゃない！
Do not apologize!
I'm not scolding you because of that!
己の努力を謝るな！
Never apologize for trying hard!
お前の努力に失礼だぞ ガイ！
じゃあ なんで…。
It's an insult to your determination, Guy!
Then why?
You're applying your self-rule
in the wrong manner!
お前は 自分ルールの
使い方を間違えている！
500周できたら
補欠合格できるなどと…。
Doing 500 laps will qualify you
for the vacant place in the academy?
That's not a self-rule!
それは自分ルールではない！
That's just a wish!
ただの願掛けだ！ お百度参りだ！
The kind you go on a pilgrimage for!
You see,
いいか 自分ルールとはな
何かに挑むにあたり→
you impose a self-rule on yourself
to spur you on
わざと 自分が過酷な状況に
追い込まれるような枷→
and help you overcome
a challenge or difficult situation.
自分だけのルールを
作ることを言うんだ。
You apply a self-rule on yourself only.
うん。
その枷があるからこそだな→
Because of that rule,
you are able to gather your strength
and focus on your efforts…
その挑戦に真剣に取り組み→
So even if you fail,
また 失敗したときは
その枷を実践することで→
applying that rule keeps you
extremely disciplined and focused.
自分を厳しく
鍛えることができる。
That is the way a self-rule works.
そうやって精進していくのが
自分ルールだ！
ごめんなさい パパ。
I'm sorry, Papa…
However, no one can find fault
in your determination.
だが お前の努力に罪はない。
Even if you can only make it half way,
たとえ 半分しか走れなくても
努力は努力。
effort is effort.
その努力に ハグだ！
And for that, you deserve a big hug!
パパ！
ガイ！
Papa!
Guy!
Oh…there they go again,
that father and son.
あれ またやってるわよ あの親子。
Isn't that abuse?
あれって虐待じゃない？
Anyway, what's with those bodysuits?
それより なんでタイツ？
キモいわね。
Gross!
応援ありがとう！
Thank you for your support!
Papa, I don't think that was support...
パパ 今のは応援じゃなくて…。
Then, encouragement.
じゃあ 声援だ。
やっぱり 僕
忍術も幻術も ダメだから→
I guess…I can't do ninjutsu or genjutsu…
だから 試験に…。
so that's why I failed the test…
Listen, Guy!
いいか ガイ！
お前の青春は始まったばかりだ。
Your youth has just begun!
青春に後ろ向きはない！
俺のように！
Do not turn your back on your youth!
Just like me!
お前が 忍術と幻術が
苦手なことは→
As your father,
I'm happy that ninjutsu
and genjutsu aren't your strong points!
むしろ パパからすれば
嬉しいことだ。
えっ？
Knowing your shortcomings
will highlight your strengths!
短所がわかれば 長所が光る！
Your taijutsu is already
shining brilliantly!
お前の体術は今から
もう光り出している！
パパは嬉しいぞ！
I'm very happy!
I've discovered my own child's strengths
when he's still so young!
その歳で もう我が子の長所に
気づけたのだからな！
パパ 本当は強がって…。
Papa, you're just saying that, aren't you?
Shortcomings can become strengths!
短所も長所になる
くどいことは丁寧なこと。
Being repetitious is just being polite!
To be loud is simply to be lively!
うるさいとは 賑やかなこと
頑固とは 一途なこと。
Obstinacy is merely earnestness!
Those who are selfish are like cats!
わがままな人は 猫みたいな人。
What about hairy people?
毛深い人は？
ね… 猫みたいな人？
Mmm... Th-They're like cats too!
胴長の人は？
What about people with long torsos…?
ね… 猫みたいな人。
Th-They're like cats!
おい マイト・ダイ。
お前 子供と また修業ごっこか？
Hey, Might Dai…
Are you playing "training"
with your son again?
You sure work hard for a perennial genin!
万年下忍がよくやるぜ。 ハッハッハ！
おう！ 応援ありがとう！
Yeah! Thanks for your support!
ったく いい歳して
何が青春だってのよ なぁ？
Damn it! Still trying to
act young at his age.
Right?
イテッ！
なんだ？
Oww!
What?!
って よく見りゃ ダイのとこのガキか
何のつもりだ？
Aren't you Dai's kid?!
What's the big idea?
Don't you ever say anything stupid
about my papa ever again!
パパを二度とバカにするな！
Stupid is as stupid does.
I just spoke the truth.
バカをバカと言って 何が悪い？
If you say one bad word about Papa,
I'll punch you five times!
パパの悪口 １回言ったら
５発ぶん殴る！
That's my self-rule!
僕の自分ルールだ！
は？ 自分ルールだ？ おもしれえ。
じゃあ 言ってやる。
Your self-rule? Interesting.
So I'll say it.
お前の親父は 忍術も幻術も
体術だってまともにできねえ→
Your dad is a good-for-nothing\
ダメ親父よ。 みんな言ってるぜ
下忍じゃねえ 芸人だってよ。
ハッハッハッハ！ 青春ネタしかできない
笑えない芸人だがな。
悪口 ２回言ったな！
10発 殴ってやる！
じゃあ 俺たちは 倍の20発だ！
クッ クソ… クソッ！
うおっ！
うっ うわっ！
(カカシ)父親のこと
ここまで言われて→
(１発も殴り返せないとはな))
♪～
≫豆助
きょうは今が旬の
アレを使った小鉢よ？
< その小鉢とは？>
< それは…>